

Contact

+855 (0) 86 72 33 27

hassothea.math@gmail.com

https://hassothea.github.io/

Phnom Penh, Cambodia

Education

PhD in Applied Math

Sorbonne Unversité, Paris, France **Topic: Theoretical & Applied ML** 2022

Master M2MO

Université Paris Diderot, Paris, France Main focus: Financial Math & Data Science 2018

Engineer of Applied Math

ENSIIE, Evry, France

Main focus: Financial Math & Data Science

2018

Bachelor of Pure Math

Royal University of Phnom Penh, Cambodia **Main focus: Pure mathematics** 2014

Language

Khmer: mother tongue English: fluent

French: conversational

Other skills

Critical & mathematical thinking

Teamwork

Communication

Time management

SOTHEA HAS

PhD in Applied Mathematics

Summary

I specialize in theoretical and applied Machine Learning (ML), Statistics, Stochastic Modeling, and Data Science, with a strong focus on atmospheric science (postdoctoral research). I am proficient in Python (including library development), PyTorch, R, C++, and MATLAB. My recent research interests focus on applying Transfer Learning Neural Networks within atmospheric science. I am also currently analyzing the dynamics of the Stochastic Gradient Descent (SGD) algorithm using Stochastic Processes.

Experience

Postdoctoral researcher Sep 2022 - Present Laboratoire de Météorologie Dynamique - ENS

- Reconstructing balloon-observed gravity wave momentum fluxes using ML and inputs from ERA5.
- Extracting important features for the reconstruction.
- Physical interpretation.
- Analyzing SGD algorithm using continuous-time stochastic processes.

PhD research

Aug 2018 - Aug 2022

LPSM - Sobronne Université

- Combine supervised and unsupervised methods for energy modeling.
- Consensual & high-dimensional aggregation methods.
- Build "gradientcobra" python library.

Teaching

UFR Mathématiques - Paris 7

Sep 2018 - Mar 2024

- Data Analysis with **R** and **Rstudio**.
- Data Mining with R and Rstudio.
- Exploratory Data Analysis with R and Rstudio.
- · Algorithm and Programming with Python.
- Big Data Technologies with Python and Spark.
- · Statistical Inference and Data Modeling.

Institute of Technology of Cambodia Sep 2024 - Present

- Statistics (Year 3)
- Exploratory Data Analysis & Unsupervised Learning (Year 5)
- Advanced Machine Learning (Master 2)

Publication

- Estimating balloon-observed gravity wave momentum fluxes using ML & input from ERA5. *Published in JGR Atmosphere*, **2024**.
- Gradient COBRA: A kernel-based consensual aggregation for regression. *Published in Journal of Data Science, Statistics and Visualization*, **2023**.
- A consensual aggregation of randomly projected high-dimensional features of predictions. Available in HAL, 2022.
- Machine learning methods applied to the global modeling of event-driven pitch angle diffusion coefficients during high-speed streams. Published in Frontiers Physics, 2022.
- KFC: A clusterwise supervised learning procedure based on aggregation of distances.
 Published in Journal of Statistical Computation and Simulation, 2021.